CHRISTOPHER HUYNH

DEVELOPER

ABOUT

Developer and Certified Scrum Master with extensive QA and project management experience. I have helped teams ship multi-year projects such as the League of Legends matchmaker revamp to millions of players worldwide. In my spare time, I am a facsimile of an amateur wildlife photographer.

CONTACT

Voice/text: (408) 694-8806 E-mail: chris.t.huynh@gmail.com

Github: chuynh18

EXPERIENCE

TA | UCLA ONLINE CODING BOOT CAMP | 2018 - PRESENT

- Co-teaching online coding boot camp after graduating from the program
- Individualized instruction and tutoring provided to students on-demand
- See portfolio section for example videos

ASSOCIATE DEVELOPMENT MANAGER | RIOT GAMES | 2016-2017 MAPS & MODES TEAM

- Assisted team with transition to Agile mindset, philosophy, practices, and processes
- Worked with team co-leads to develop new team mission and vision as the team transitioned to a new home in the organization
- Helped kick off initial Scrum rituals and artifacts until the team was ready to self-manage and own its own process
- Helped project manage work items being done by external teams and contractors

ASSOCIATE DEVELOPMENT MANAGER | RIOT GAMES | 2014-2016 PLAYER BEHAVIOR TEAM

- Helped team deliver headline features to League of Legends such as two new matchmaking systems and player behavior features such as Honor and Tribunal
- Helped facilitate sprintly Scrum rituals along with larger scale project and ad hoc retrospectives
- Project management roles varied depending on project phase.
 - Project inception: Design docs and product proposals complete, organization is bought in, initial backlog creation, risk analysis, team staffing
 - Development: Facilitate sprintly rituals, faciliate monthly meeting with team discipline leads to get ahead of any bumps in the road, keeping wider organization informed and ensuring that team is always unblocked
 - Pre-launch: Launch planning and risk mitigation, working with partner teams, infrastructure teams, and partner companies to ensure the organization is ready for launch
 - Ready for launch means we have publishing plans in place, infrastructure teams are ready
 to support the additional load of our features, monitoring is in place for live support teams,
 other development teams are aware we are on the runway and understand the implication
 of our feature's launch on their work and features

• Launch: Arrange travel for appropriate team members to support overseas partners, broadcast information on launch and activation to the wider engineering organization, ensure all learnings from launch process are captured and reflected in our backlog as appropriate

QUALITY ASSURANCE ANALYST | RIOT GAMES | 2011-2014 VARIOUS TEAMS

- Worked hand-in-hand on cross-functional teams to support the sustainable development of features on League of Legends
- Black box software testing done in close coordination with developers. Wrote test plans based on understanding of upcoming features based on design and engineering specifications and conversations with team members.
- Helped teams assess the quality of their output: Did we build the right thing? Did we build the thing right?
- Acted as teams' main point of contact with external test contractors
- · Assisted with bi-weekly League of Legends deploys

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

UC BERKELEY EXTENSION | 2018

Full-stack web developer coding boot camp

SCRUM ALLIANCE | 2014

Certified Scrum Master

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY | 2011

Bachelor of Arts, Southeast Asian Studies

SELECTED WORKS

Four in a row

https://chuynh18.github.io/fourinarow/

Connect Four clone written in vanilla HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Complete with Al opponent. Documentation and retrospective can be found in the README in the GitHub repo.

Shiritori

https://chuynh18.github.io/shiritori/

Japanese rhyming game written in vanilla HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Has a small built-in Japanese dictionary cobbled together from online resources. Romanizes Hiragana and Katakana to Romaji. Written in collaboration with Cliff Pham (GitHub: cliffpham).

Snake

https://chuynh18.github.io/snake/

Snake clone written in vanilla HTML, CSS, and Javascript. I wanted to try my hand at something a little more real-time. This helped me get my feet wet with the Chrome debugger and profiler as I optimized performance on mobile devices.

TA tutoring videos - clickable links

Helping a student with debugging an assignment

Deeper dive into OOP with JavaScript: factories, constructors, classes with public and private data